So, now that we have a PDS dataset, you probably want to do something with it.
既然我們已有 PDS 資料集，接下來你可能想對它做些事情。
In this lesson, we'll go through the process of creating, editing, and displaying members
本課程將介紹建立、編輯及顯示成員的流程
in a PDS.
在 PDS 中。
We're going to be using the Edit Entry panel, and you get there from option 2 off of the
我們將使用 Edit Entry 面板，從主 ISPF 面板選擇選項 2 進入。
main ISPF panel.
主 ISPF 面板。
To create a new dataset member in an existing PDS, enter the name of the dataset on the
要在現有 PDS 中建立新成員，請於 Edit Entry 面板輸入資料集名稱。
Edit Entry panel.
Edit Entry 面板上。
And again, you can see here you can use the handy three fields, or you can enter the full
你可以使用方便的三個欄位，也可以直接在下方欄位輸入完整資料集名稱。
dataset name into the field below it.
你也可以直接在下方欄位輸入完整的資料集名稱。
Notice that there's a fourth field in the bottom for member.
注意下方還有第四個成員欄位。
That's where you put the name of the member that you're creating.
這裡放您要建立的成員名稱。
Or if you're using the field below, you're going to spell out the name of the member
或者如果您使用下面的欄位，請以括號方式拼寫成員名稱
at the end of the PDS in parentheses.
在 PDS 結尾處。
For example, i-n-s-t-j-r-g-dot-e-s-ten-dot-p-d-s-parentheses-member-one-parentheses, where the first three parts
例如，i-n-s-t-j-r-g-dot-e-s-ten-dot-p-d-s-(m ember-one)，前三個部分
make up the PDS name, and member one is the name of the member.
組成 PDS 名稱，member-one 是成員名稱。
So fill those out either way, and then hit enter.
請以任一種方式填寫，然後按 Enter。
This will open up the ISPF editor.
這將開啟 ISPF 編輯器。
To start typing into this member, move your cursor into the empty area towards the right,
要開始在此成員輸入文字，將游標移到右側的空白區域，
and then start typing.
然後開始輸入。
You can type on multiple lines, just don't type over on the left column yet.
您可以輸入多行，但暫時不要觸碰左邊欄位。
When you're done, hit enter, and you'll see numbers appear over on the left there.
完成後按 Enter，左側會出現編號。
These are the record numbers, and when you want to save your masterpiece, type save up
這些是記錄號碼，想儲存作品時，輸入 save up
top and hit enter.
top 後按 Enter。
The top line of your screen shows the name of the dataset and the member that you're
畫面頂端顯示你正在編輯的 dataset 和 member 名稱。
editing.
正在編輯中。
This is a good way to verify that you have the correct dataset and member selected.
這是確認選對 dataset 與 member 的好方法。
To display the members in a dataset, go back to that edit entry panel.
要顯示 dataset 中的成員，回到編輯輸入介面。
Put in the name of the dataset without specifying any members, and hit enter.
輸入 dataset 名稱，不指定 member，然後按 Enter。
In this example, there are six members in the dataset i-n-s-t-j-r-g-dot-e-s-ten-dot-p-d-s.
範例中，dataset i-n-s-t-j-r-g-dot-e-s-ten-dot -p-d-s 有六個成員。
We can edit any of those by placing the letter e next to them and then hitting enter.
可在想編輯的成員旁輸入字母 e，然後按 Enter。
This brings up the editor again.
這會再次開啟編輯器。
Another way to display the members in a dataset is from the dataset list utility.
另一種顯示資料集成員的方法是使用資料集清單工具。
You get there from the first ISPF screen, option three for utilities, and then option
從第一個 ISPF 螢幕進入，選擇第三項工具，再選擇
four for DS list.
第四項 DS 清單。
From the DS list utility screen, enter the high level qualifier in the DS name level
在 DS 清單工具螢幕，於 DS 名稱層級欄位輸入最高層級限定字，
field, and don't enter anything in the option field, just hit enter.
不要在選項欄輸入任何東西，直接按 Enter。
It'll come back and show you all of the datasets that start with that high level qualifier.
系統會回傳並顯示所有以該最高層級限定字開頭的資料集。
You can then tab to the left of the dataset you want to view and enter a forward slash.
接著可以跳到欲查看資料集的左側，輸入正斜線（/）。
A list of options will pop up.
一個選項清單會跳出來。
Option four of that list is member list, and that's just what we want, so type four and
清單中的第四項是成員清單，這正是我們要的，輸入 4 即可。
hit enter.
按下 Enter 鍵。
What if you're in a dataset member and you want to add some new lines to it, some new
如果你在資料集成員中，想新增一些新行
records?
紀錄？
That's easy, and we get to use that left column for this one.
這很簡單，我們可以使用左側欄位。
Move your cursor over to the line you want to add lines underneath and type an i.
將游標移到想在其下方新增行的那一行，然後輸入 i。
A new line appears, and here's a helpful tip.
出現新行，這裡有個實用提示。
If you want to add five lines, you type i5 and then hit enter, and you can do the same
如果你想新增五行，輸入 i5 後按 Enter，你也可以這樣做
kind of thing for eight lines, nine lines, or 20 lines, but let's not get too crazy here.
類似八行、九行或二十行的東西，但別太複雜。
You can now add data to these lines, just like you did when you were first creating
您現在可以向這些行添加資料，就像您剛開始建立時一樣
that member.
該成員。
Hit enter when you're done, and those lines with data get turned into records, and any
完成後按下 Enter，那些有資料的行會變成記錄，
lines with no data, they go away.
沒有資料的行就會消失。
We can delete lines too.
我們也可以刪除行。
Here we have a member called member two.
這裡有一個名為 member two 的成員。
To delete a line, place a single d followed by a space next to that line.
要刪除行，在該行旁輸入 d 和一個空格。
Now, the reason for the space is that it's just safer.
空格的原因是比較安全。
We know that we're only deleting one line that way.
這樣我們確定只刪除一行。
Hit enter, and then boom, it's gone.
按 Enter，行就消失了。
And just like insert, if we want to delete five lines, I can type d5.
和插入類似，若要刪除五行，我可以輸入 d5。
You get it, pretty simple stuff.
你懂了，很簡單的操作。
ISPF also has block commands, so to move a block of text, enter mm on the first line
ISPF也有區塊命令，移動一段文字時，第一行輸入mm
of text you want to move, and then another mm on the last line of text you want to move.
想移動的文字區塊第一行輸入mm，最後一行也輸入mm。
Then in the spot where you want to move it, place an a for after or a b or before to tell
在要移動到的位置輸入a（後置）或b（前置），告訴它是要移動在該行前或後。
it whether you want to move that block of text before or after that line.
告訴它你想把該文字區塊移動到該行前或後。
As you can imagine, there are a lot of line commands we can use in the editor.
可以想像，在編輯器裡有許多行命令可用。
Here's a listing of just some of them which you can use during your lab exercises.
這裡列出部分可於實驗中使用的命令。